<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <!-- App title -->
    <string name="title">Scrambled Net</string>

    <string name="description">A computer networking puzzle game</string>

    <string name="splash_text">
        <b>Scrambled Net</b>
        \n\n
        Connect the terminals to the server by rotating the tiles
        \n\n
        Touch a tile to rotate it; press and hold a tile to lock it when you think it\'s correct.
        \n\n
        Use the menu to select different skill levels, pause the game, or start a new game.\n\n
        See the help in the menu for a full user\'s guide.\n\n
        <b>Tap the screen to start.</b>
    </string>

    <!-- Help texts for specific skill levels -->
    <string name="help_master">At Master level, the board edges wrap around; cells on the right
        edge connect to those on the left edge, and vice versa. Similarly for the top and bottom
        edges
    </string>

    <string name="help_insane">At Insane level, the board edges wrap around; cells on the right
        edge connect to those on the left edge, and vice versa. Similarly for the top and bottom
        edges. But in addition, in cells with 3 or 4 connections, the wiring is invisible. Good luck!
    </string>

    <string name="about_text">An Android puzzle game by Ian Cameron Smith
        \nMaintained by Michael Mueller
        \nInspired by KNetwalk by Andi Peredri, Thomas Nagy, and Reinhold Kainhofer
        \n
        \nFor information and source code see the project home page
        \n
        \nThis program is open-source software; you can redistribute it and/or modify it under the
        terms of the GNU General Public License as published by the Free Software Foundation;
        either version 2 of the License, or (at your option) any later version
        \n
        \nThis program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful, but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY;
        without even the implied warranty of MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.
        See the GNU General Public License at
        <a href="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl-2.0.html">gnu.org</a> for more details
    </string>

    <!-- Scores list strings -->
    <string name="scores_title">Personal Bests</string>
    <string name="scores_clickstitle">Fewest Clicks</string>
    <string name="scores_timestitle">Fastest Time</string>
    <string name="scores_skill">Skill Level</string>
    <string name="scores_clicks">Clicks</string>
    <string name="scores_time">Time</string>
    <string name="scores_when">When</string>
    <string name="menu_scores_reset">Reset all scores</string>

    <!-- Text displayed in pause mode -->
    <string name="pause_text">
        <b>Game Paused</b>
        \n
        \nTap to continue
    </string>

    <!-- Win dialog strings -->
    <string name="win_title"><b>You win!</b></string>
    <string name="win_pbest_title"><b>New Personal Best!</b></string>
    <string name="win_text">Congratulations! You solved the puzzle in %1$d:%2$02d, using %3$d clicks</string>
    <string name="win_spares_text">Congratulations! You solved the puzzle in %1$d:%2$02d, using %3$d clicks, and with %4$d pieces left over!</string>
    <string name="best_clicks_text">That\'s your best click count yet at this level!</string>
    <string name="best_time_text">That\'s your fastest time yet at this level!</string>
    <string name="best_both_text">That\'s your best click count and fastest time yet at this level!</string>
    <string name="win_finish">Tap "New Game" for a new game, or "Continue" to experiment with this layout</string>
    <string name="win_new">New Game</string>
    <string name="win_continue">Continue</string>
    <string name="about_title">About</string>

    <!-- Button strings -->
    <string name="button_ok">OK</string>
    <string name="button_close">Close</string>
    <string name="button_license">Show license</string>
    <string name="button_homepage">Home page</string>

    <!-- Menu strings -->
    <string name="menu_game_new">New game</string>
    <string name="menu_game_pause">Pause</string>
    <string name="menu_show_scores">High scores</string>
    <string name="menu_set_skill">Skill level</string>
    <string name="menu_sound">Sound</string>
    <string name="menu_anim">Animation</string>
    <string name="menu_autosolve">Auto solve</string>
    <string name="menu_stopsolve">Stop solving</string>
    <string name="menu_help">Help</string>
    <string name="menu_about">About</string>
    <string name="no_sounds">Mute</string>
    <string name="quiet_sounds">Quiet</string>
    <string name="play_sounds">Loud</string>
    <string name="anim_off">Off</string>
    <string name="anim_on">On</string>

    <!-- Skill levels. -->
    <string name="skill_mode">Mode</string>
    <string name="skill_novice">Easy</string>
    <string name="skill_normal">Normal</string>
    <string name="skill_expert">Hard</string>
    <string name="skill_master">Harder</string>
    <string name="skill_insane">Insane</string>

    <!-- URLs. -->
    <string name="url_license">http://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl-2.0.html</string>
    <string name="url_homepage">https://www.silentservices.de</string>

    <!-- Help texts -->
    <string name="help_intro">
        Scrambled Net is a simple puzzle game which requires you to sort
        out the connections in a computer network, so that all the terminals are
        connected to the server.  The network is made up of tiles, and while all
        the tiles are in the right place, they have been rotated randomly into a
        useless mess.\n\
        \n\
        You need to rotate individual tiles to re-connect the network.
        Tiles which are connected to the server are shown highlighted.  When all
        terminals are connected, you\'ve won.\n\
        \n\
        It may seem simple at first, but try working your way up through the five
        difficulty levels.  You may think the novice level is a blast, but
        I guarantee it gets more challenging when some of the tiles are invisible!
        If it gets too hard, try the hints below.\n\
    </string>

    <string name="help_HowToPlay_Title">
        How to play
    </string>

    <string name="help_HowToPlay_Content">
        Use the menu to select different skill levels, pause the game, or start a new game
        \n\n
        Tap a tile to rotate it once clockwise. Keep tapping until the tile is in the right orientation;
        if you need multiple turns to get it pointing the right way, that\'s still
        only counted as one click.
        \n\n
        If you think that you have set a tile correctly, you can lock it in place.  To lock a tile, press and hold
        the tile for a second; it will click and turn darker to indicate
        that it is locked.  If you try to rotate a locked tile, it will display a
        flashing highlight.  You can unlock it again by pressing and holding it.
        \n\n
        Bear in mind that locking a tile is no indication that it is correct
        \n
    </string>

    <string name="help_Difficulties_Title">
        Difficulties
    </string>

    <string name="help_Difficulties_Content">
        Scrambled Net has five levels of difficulty. Higher skill levels
        have larger boards, and the most advanced levels have some special features:\n\
        \n\
        • <b>Novice</b> gives you a small board to play with.\n\
        \n\
        • <b>Normal</b> level has a somewhat larger board.\n\
        \n\
        • <b>Expert</b> level uses a large board.\n\
        \n\
        • <b>Master</b> level also uses a large board; but as an added challenge,
        the board \"wraps around\".  This means that a connection can go off the right
        edge, for example, and connect to the corresponding tile on the left edge;
        the same applies to the top and bottom edges.  Also, you\'ll find some 4-way
        connections thrown in to the mix.\n\
        \n\
        • <b>Insane</b> level is the same as Master, but with the wrinkle that all
        3-way and 4-way connections are invisible!  You\'ll find that you need to
        figure out a whole new set of deductions to complete an insane puzzle.  Be
        assured, though, that it <i>can</i> be done!\n\
        \n\
        One last note: to take full advantage of your device\'s capabilities, the
        actual number of tiles in a board is different for different devices
    </string>

    <string name="help_Menu_Title">
        Settings
    </string>

    <string name="help_Menu_Content">
            The settings menu contains a number of options:\n\
            \n\
            • <b>New game</b> starts a new game, abandoning the current game if any.\n\
            \n\
            • <b>Pause</b> pauses the game, and covers the screen.  Tap the screen
            to un-pause.\n\
            \n\
            • <b>High scores</b> displays a table of your personal best scores — both
            the fewest clicks in which you\'ve solved each difficulty level, and the
            fastest time.  You can use the menu to reset your scores.  Press \"Back\"
            to get back to the game.\n\
            \n\
            • <b>Skill level</b> prompts you to select a skill level, then starts
            a new game at that skill level.\n\
            \n\
            • <b>Solve it!</b> runs an autosolver to finish the current puzzle for you.
            If you get completely stuck, you can use this to see the solution — but
            you won\'t get personal best credit!  While solving, this menu item
            changes to a \"Stop\" button, so you can stop the autosolver at any time.\n\
            \n\
            • <b>Sound</b> lets you set your preferred sound effects level.  However,
            the sound effects volume can always be adjusted in the game using the hardware
            volume keys.  If no sound is coming out, try turning up the volume using
            the buttons.\n\
            \n\
            • <b>Animation</b> lets you turn the \"network data\" animation on or off.\n\
            \n\
            • <b>Help</b> displays this help.\n\
            \n\
            • <b>About</b> displays version and license information
    </string>

    <string name="help_Hints_Title">
        Hints
    </string>

    <string name="help_Hints_Content">
        <item>Novice
            The edges are a good place to start - remember that a connection
            can never go off the edge of the board, so any tile which connects
            that way must be wrong.  If a tile connects out to the right, then the
            next tile to the right must connect back to the left.  In this way,
            once you have figured out one tile, you know something about the
            adjacent tiles.\n\
            \n\
            A tile which does <b>not</b> connect in a given direction also
            tells you something about the next tile in that direction
        </item>

        <item>Normal
            You can <i>sometimes</i> finish a level without using all the tiles;
            but you can <b>always</b> finish a level by using all the tiles.  So you
            may assume that all tiles must have a valid connection.\n\
            \n\
            Keep track of which tiles you <b>know</b> are correct by locking
            them - press and hold a tile to lock it (see \"Playing the Game\"
            above).  But be sure that you really have them correct
        </item>

        <item>Expert
            Expert mode is just the same as before, only larger - don\'t be
            discouraged!\n\
            \n\
            Terminals always have exactly one connection, and all terminals have to
            connect to the server.  If two terminals connect together without a
            branch, there\'s no way to hook them to the server; so that must be
            wrong
        </item>

        <item>Master
            In Master level, the edges no longer help you.  Look for blocks of
            terminals together, and remember that two terminals can\'t be connected
            directly together.  When you figure out one tile, look for all possible
            deductions you can make based on it
        </item>

        <item>Insane
            In Insane level, you will need to make use of all the deductions you
            have figured out, plus at least one new one.  Remember that only 3-way
            and 4-way tiles are invisible; so an invisible tile can often tell you
            something about its neighbours
        </item>

    </string>

</resources>
